Hello.  Today we will talk a little about the latest quarterly results of ICICI LB for
Q1 2026.
So let us try to understand these financial
figures in simple language and
see what the company is doing?  How are you
doing?  So let's get straight to the numbers.  First of all,
total income means total income.
In this quarter it has been Rs 683 crore.  We had
5851 crores in the last quarter and
5351 crores in the same quarter last year, so it
means it is increasing,
yes this growth seems to be quite consistent,
if we look at it year on year, it is about 14% higher
and about 4% more than the previous quarter, so
this is a sign of a good steady growth, in
my opinion
14% year on year is quite good and 4%
quarter on quarter is also fine, well the income has
increased, now let us take a look at the expenses also.  The
company spent Rs 5429 crore in this quarter.
Good.
In the last quarter this figure was Rs 5435 crore
and last year it was Rs 4850 crore.
So the interesting thing here is that the
expenses have reduced a bit compared to the previous quarter.  Not
much but it has reduced.
Whereas income had increased.  Yes, this is a good thing.
And expenses will definitely increase year after year
because the business is growing.  But
it is good to keep control on quarterly basis.
Shows efficiency.   You are
right.   So that
means income is going up.  If expenses are almost
flat or slightly down, then
what happened to profits?  Our net profit
this quarter was Rs 747 crore.
747 crores.
Yes.  It was Rs 519 crore in the last quarter and Rs
580 crore in the same quarter last year.
This is a tremendous jump.  Meaning, even if we look at it year after year, there is an
increase of about 30% which is
very good.
Yes.  But if we compare it with the previous quarter, from Rs
519 crore to Rs 747 crore, this is a
jump of about 4550%.
45-50% quarterly increase is really a
huge jump and there is another thing related to this.  The
market was expecting
analysts to estimate that the profit would
probably be around ₹620 crore.
Well,
only ₹620
yes and the company delivered ₹747 crore.
Wow, that means performance much better than expected.
this is so awesome.  When a company
beats market estimates by such a large margin, it is considered quite positive.
Absolutely and its effect is
also visible on earnings per share i.e. EPS.  It has increased to
₹15.16 this quarter.
We were at
₹11.77 last year and ₹10.29 in the previous quarter.
Yes.  So, a good increase is being seen in EPS as well,
which
is also logical in terms of net profit.
This is good news for shareholders.  But one thing that is
visible in the results is that the company has left the NPA
section of non-performing assets
blank.  No data has been
taken there.
NPA in insurance company results.  This is
not a bit strange.  This happens mostly for banks.
Yes, if it happens then it would be more relevant for the banks.
Regarding their loans.
In insurance companies, this may be
related to their investment portfolio.
Meaning perhaps an investment that has
stopped giving returns.  But yes,
not giving the figures attracts a little attention.
Yes, I mean, in terms of transparency, it would have been
better if you had told something.  Well, it is possible that there may
not be any specific reason or the amount may be
very small.  It's hard to say without data.
But yes, there is one point worth noting.
Ok.  So if we sum it all up, the income has
increased well.  Expenses are under control.  Profits have
come in much higher than expected and EPS
is also quite decent.
Absolutely.  Overall, these first quarter
numbers look quite strong for ICICI Lambar.  This is
a good start to this
financial year.  So, in short,
ICIC Lambd has shown good
year-on-year and quarter-on-quarter growth in both revenue and profits in Q1 2026
and has
also surpassed analyst estimates by a significant margin.
Yes, this performance definitely shows the
good health of the company and the efficiency of the management.
Thanks Alina and Gautam for your input.  If
you found our expert's advice correct, then
like and share the video.
Also, please subscribe to the channel